<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="project-plan-render.xsl"?>
<plan xmlns="http://www.eclipse.org/project/plan"
	xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
	<release projectid="technology.linuxtools" version="1.0" />
	<introduction>
		<html:h1>This document is a work in progress</html:h1>
		<html:p>
			The Linux Tools/Linux Distros project is a two-faceted
			project. Firstly, it provides a place for Linux
			distributions to collaboratively overcome issues surrounding
			distribution packaging of Eclipse technology. The project
			produces both best practices and tools related to packaging.
			Secondly, the project develops and produces tools relevant
			to Linux developers.
		</html:p>
	</introduction>
	<release_deliverables>
		<html:p>
			The Linux Tools/Linux Distros project delivers tools as
			Eclipse plugins which are used primarily by Linux developers
			and packagers. The project also aims to deliver various
			scripts, techniques, and tarballs which ease the process of
			packaging Eclipse technology for Linux distributions.
		</html:p>
	</release_deliverables>
	<release_milestones>
		<milestone date="2008-11-01" milestone="M1">
			<html:p>Milestone one towards 1.0 release</html:p>
			<html:p>
				Latest ChangeLog and specfile editor releases, first cut
				towards 3.4.1 SDK packaging tools (patches, scripts,
				etc.), first release of plugin building and packaging
				tools, patches used to run SDK test suite, re-namespaced
				OProfile plugins.
			</html:p>
		</milestone>
		<milestone date="2008-12-01" milestone="M2">
			<html:p>Milestone two towards 1.0 release</html:p>
			<html:p>
				Autotools plugins, improved 3.4.1 SDK packaging tools,
				plugin building scripts, bug fixes in specfile editor
				and ChangeLog as needed, cleanups and UI revamping in
				OProfile plugin.
			</html:p>
		</milestone>
		<milestone date="2009-01-15" milestone="RC">
			<html:p>Release candidate for 1.0 release</html:p>
			<html:p>
				No new functionality. Bug fixes and final work towards
				3.4.2 SDK packaging tools.
			</html:p>
		</milestone>
		<milestone date="2009-03-01" milestone="1.0">
			<html:p>1.0 release</html:p>
			<html:p>
				Packaging: SDK packaging tools (specifically 3.4.2),
				plugin building scripts, testing scripts. Linux
				development: autotools, ChangeLog, OProfile.
			</html:p>
		</milestone>
		<postamble />
	</release_milestones>
	<target_environments>
		<html:p>
			The tools run with Eclipse 3.4 (some may still require
			updating from 3.3 in places) and require Java 5.0. Some
			tools may require CDT 5.0.0.
		</html:p>
		<html:p>
			The packaging tools not delivered as Eclipse plugins have
			varying requirements but generally require basic tools such
			as bash, sed, awk, grep, etc.
		</html:p>
		<internationalization>
			<html:p>
				The tools aim to have all strings externalized so as to
				facilitate internationalization. At present, no
				translations are provided.
			</html:p>
		</internationalization>
	</target_environments>
	<compatibility_with_previous_releases />

	<themes_and_priorities>
		<preamble>
			<html:p>
				The Linux Distros/Linux Tools project differs in aims
				from many Eclipse projects. It enables adopters of
				Eclipse technology but often through help with
				consumption and not through APIs. It also aims to be a
				place for collaboration among Linux distributions.
				Finally, the project aims to bring Eclipse technology to
				Linux developers by providing tools targetted at Linux
				developers -- specifically those programming in C and
				C++.
			</html:p>
		</preamble>
		<theme
			name="Getting the Eclipse SDK into Linux distributions">
			<description>
				<html:p>
					Most Linux distributions require all packages
					included therein to be built directly from source
					code. This theme encompasses the project goal of
					assisting distributions in their building and
					packaging of the Eclipse SDK as well as
					standardizing practices and any patches needed. It
					also aims to encourage and aid distributions in
					their attempts to drive unit test results down to
					zero.
				</html:p>
			</description>
			<committed bugzilla=""></committed>
		</theme>
		<theme name="Getting plugins into Linux distributions">
			<description>
				<html:p>
					Getting plugins into Linux distributions relates to
					the project's goal of making it easier to build and
					package Eclipse plugins for Linux distributions. At
					present it includes shell scripts and best practice
					documentation. In the future, we aim to provide
					Eclipse plugins to help packagers.
				</html:p>
			</description>
			<committed bugzilla=""></committed>
		</theme>
		<theme name="Make OProfile easy to use from within Eclipse">
			<description>
				<html:p>
					OProfile is a very commonly used Linux profiling
					tool. The project aims to deliver seamless
					OProfile-based profiling of CDT projects, integrated
					into the workbench.
				</html:p>
			</description>
			<committed
				bugzilla="https://bugs.eclipse.org/bugs/buglist.cgi?query_format=advanced&amp;short_desc_type=allwordssubstr&amp;short_desc=&amp;classification=Technology&amp;product=Linux+Distros&amp;component=OProfile&amp;long_desc_type=allwordssubstr&amp;long_desc=&amp;bug_file_loc_type=allwordssubstr&amp;bug_file_loc=&amp;status_whiteboard_type=allwordssubstr&amp;status_whiteboard=&amp;keywords_type=allwords&amp;keywords=&amp;bug_status=UNCONFIRMED&amp;bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED">
			</committed>
		</theme>
		<theme
			name="Integrate the GNU Autotools into the Eclipse workbench">
			<description>
				<html:p>
					This part of the project allows projects that are
					built using the GNU Autools (automake, autoconf,
					etc.) to be developed using the CDT. It relies upon
					the CDT build mechanisms. The project anticipates
					submission of this code contribution in Q4 2008 to
					be quickly followed up with an IP review submission.
					Future goals include managing new file addition to
					targets, small wizards to ease creation of various
					build targets, and tools to export an "autotooled"
					build.
				</html:p>
			</description>
		</theme>
	</themes_and_priorities>
	<appendix />
</plan>
